Tales of the Black Freighter is a animation, action,
adventure film directed by Daniel DelPurgatorio.
A mariner survives an attack from the dreaded pirates of the Black Freighter,
but his struggle to return home to warn it has a horrific cost.
The Mariner (voice), played by Gerard Butler.
Ridley (voice), played by Jared Harris.
Money Lender (voice), played by Cam Clarke.
Sea Captain's Daughter (voice), played by Siobhan Flynn.
Sea Captain's Daughter (voice), played by Salli Saffioti.
Sea Captain's Wife (voice), played by Lori Tritel.
Watchmen is a comic book limited series by the British creative team of writer
Alan Moore, artist Dave Gibbons, and colorist John Higgins.
It was published monthly by DC Comics in 1986 and 1987 before
being collected in a single-volume edition in 1987.
Watchmen originated from a story proposal Moore submitted to DC featuring
superhero characters that the company had acquired from Charlton Comics.
As Moore's proposed story would have left many of the characters unusable for future stories,
managing editor Dick Giordano convinced Moore to create original characters instead.
Moore used the story as a means of reflecting contemporary anxieties, deconstructing
and satirizing the superhero concept, and making political commentary.
Watchmen depicts an alternate history in which superheroes emerged in the 1940s and 1960s and their presence changed
history so that the United States won the Vietnam War and the Watergate scandal was never exposed.
In 1985, the country is edging toward World War III with the Soviet Union, freelance costumed vigilantes have
been outlawed and most former superheroes are in retirement or working for the government.
The story focuses on the protagonists' personal development and moral struggles as an investigation
into the murder of a government-sponsored superhero pulls them out of retirement.
Gibbons uses a nine-panel grid layout throughout the series and adds
recurring symbols such as a blood-stained smiley face.
All but the last issue feature supplemental fictional documents that add to the series' backstory and the narrative is intertwined with
that of another story, an in-story pirate comic titled Tales of the Black Freighter, which one of the characters reads.
Structured at times as a nonlinear narrative, the story
skips through space, time, and plot.
In the same manner, entire scenes and dialogues have parallels with others
through synchronicity, coincidence, and repeated imagery.
A commercial success, Watchmen has received critical
acclaim both in the comics and mainstream press.
Watchmen was recognized in Time's List of the 100 Best Novels as one of
the best English language novels published since 1923.
In a retrospective review, the BBC's Nicholas Barber
described it as "the moment comic books grew up".
Moore opposed this idea, stating, "I tend to think
that, no, comics hadn't grown up.
There were a few titles that were more adult than people were used to.
But the majority of comics titles were pretty much the same as they'd ever been.
It wasn't comics growing up.
I think it was more comics meeting the emotional age of the audience coming the other way."
After several
attempts to adapt the series into a feature film, director Zack Snyder's Watchmen was released in 2009.
An episodic video game, Watchmen: The End Is Nigh, was
released to coincide with the film's release.
DC Comics published Before Watchmen, a series of nine prequel miniseries, in 2012, and Doomsday Clock, a 12-issue limited series
and sequel to the original Watchmen series, from 2017 to 2019 – both without Moore's or Gibbons' involvement.
The second series integrated the Watchmen characters within the DC Universe.
A standalone sequel, Rorschach by Tom King, was published
between October 2020 and September 2021.
A television continuation to the original comic, set 34 years after the comic's timeline,
was broadcast on HBO from October to December 2019 with Gibbons' involvement.
Moore has expressed his displeasure with adaptations and sequels of
Watchmen and asked his name not to be used for future works.
The film explores themes of pirate, journey home, short film, irony.
The tone is dark.